Guide to the Bob Berenson Papers, 1950-2004 and undated RL.11101
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Bob Berenson Papers, 1950-2004 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Berenson, Bob (Robert Leonard)
RL.11101
14.0 Linear Feet
Advertising executive with Grey Advertising, Inc.
Arrangement
Arranged into three series: Manila File; Office Files; and Audiovisual Materials.
Biographical / Historical
BA/BA in journalism and marketing from Syracuse University; MS from Medill School of Journalism, Northwestern University. Began 1964 as Assistant Account Executive at Grey Advertising. Career at Grey: Executive Vice President 1977; President, Grey/NY 1993; Chairman/General Manager Grey Global Group 1999; retired 2005.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
However, original audiovisual materials are closed to research until use copies can be produced.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Bob Berenson Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2005.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections: Caroline Bien Papers; Alvin Achenbaum Papers; J. Walter Thompson Company Advertising Vertical Files.
Collection Overview
Collection spans 1950-2004 and includes speeches, newsletters and other publications; research and strategy reports, audiovisual materials and other materials documenting administration and management of the Grey agency. The collection also touches on activities of other WPP subsidiary agencies. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising; Advertising executives -- History -- 20th century; Advertising -- Management; Advertising agencies -- United States; Berenson, Bob (Robert Leonard)
- Manila File, 1950-2002 and undated; 1
  - 1. Trends, 1969-1975 (Box 1)
  - 2. Robert Townsend, Up the Organization (Harper's), 1970 Mar. (Box 1)
  - 3. John Monsarrat, The Case for a Full Service Agency, 1971 (Box 1)
  - 4. Alvin Achenbaum, Advertising Doesn't Manipulate Consumers, 1972 (Box 1)
  - 5. Management of New Product Development, 1971 (Box 1)
  - 6. How Do You Tackle the Leader--AAAA speech, 1974 (Box 1)
  - 7. David Ogilvy, Three Cheers for Madison Avenue, 1974 (Box 1)
  - 8. John Marder, Understanding Marketing--speech, 1974 (Box 1)
  - 9. Bill Foster, Three Kinds of Business, undated (Box 1)
  - 10. Don Emmit, Soliloquoy, 1971 (Box 1)
  - 11. George Ferrand, How to Run an Agency for Fun and Profit, undated (Box 1)
  - 12. Reasons Why a House Agency Is Especially Not Suitable for the Canada Dry Corporation, undated (Box 1)
  - 13. Richard Lessler, Society's Woes and Corporate Advertising: The Cure That Can Kill--speech, 1971 (Box 1)
  - 14. Alvin Achenbaum, Is the Government Our Only Problem?--speech, 1971 (Box 1)
  - 15. Fact vs. Folklore in Agency Business--Analyst speech, 1969 (Box 1)
  - 16. Grey Matter, 1970 (Box 1)
  - 17. Ben Wattenburg, Demography of the 1970s: The Birth Dearth and What It Means, 1971 (Box 1)
  - 18. How to Catch Up to Leading Brands in Packaged Goods Markets (Nowland Keys #119), undated (Box 1)
  - 19. David Ogilvy, Principles of Management, 1968 (Box 1)
  - 20. TV Effectiveness Revolution--speech; Edward Meyer, Is the Golden Goose Beginning to Lay Leaden Eggs?, undated (Box 1)
  - 21. New Car Purchase Behavior Model, 1972 (Box 1)
  - 22. Thomas Benham, Trends in Public Attitudes Towards Business and Free Enterprise, undated (Box 1)
  - 23. Test Market Analysis, 1975 (Box 1)
  - 24. ARF 1974 speeches (Box 1)
  - 25. Rena Bartos, Consumer's View of Advertising, 1975 (Box 1)
  - 26. Jock Elliott, What (Gloomy) Gus Says and What I Say Back, 1975 (Box 1)
  - 27. Edward Meyer, Keynot address to Grey annual meeting, 1975 (Box 1)
  - 28. W.R. Hesse (President, AAAA), Advertising is for Selling, 1978 (Box 1)
  - 29. Ibrahimn Hefzallah and W. Paul Maloney, Are There Only Six Kinds of TV Commercials, 1979 (Box 1)
  - 30. Theodore Gordon (Futures), American Society: Emergence of the New Power Blocs, 1980 (Box 1)
  - 31. Whit Hobbs, The Perfect Client, 1980 (Box 1)
  - 32. William Bernbach, Facts Are Not Enough, 1980 (Box 1)
  - 33. Stephen K. Zimmerman, Increasing Advertising Productivity, 1980 (Box 1)
  - 34. Whit Hobbs, How to Make a Speech, 1980 (Box 1)
  - 35. Training Tips to Develop Analytical Ability, 1980 (Box 1)
  - 36. Nancy Giges, Magazine Comparative Ads: Better Than...?, Ad Age, 1980 Sept. 22 (Box 1)
  - 37. New TV Technologies: What Do They Mean to National Advertising?, Grey Media Department, 1980 Aug. (Box 1)
  - 38. Nancy Posternak (Research), Principles for Higher Recall, 1980 Oct. 10 (Box 1)
  - 39. S. Young, Brand Character and Trends in Buying--Retail speech, undated (Box 1)
  - 40. Lou Harris, Advertiser's View of Client-Agency Relationship, 1980 (Box 1)
  - 41. A Conversation with David Ogilvy--Ad Age, 1981 Sept. 14 (Box 1)
  - 42. PACT: Positioning-Advertising-Copy-Testing, A Consensus Credo, undated (Box 1)
  - 43. Jerrold Simon, How to Write a Resume, undated (Box 1)
  - 44. [empty folder] (Box 1)
  - 45. Carl Hixon, Leo Burnett, 1982 (Box 1)
  - 46. Edward Meyer, speech on positioning concept, undated (Box 2)
  - 47. James Heekin, Continuing Questions: Why Advertising Agencies Lose Accounts, and How to Avoid It?, Ad Age, 1978 July 24 (Box 2)
  - 48. Edward Mayer, Advertising Agencies as They Relate to the Economy, 1973 (Box 2)
  - 49. Rudyard Berenson, Gunga Maloof, undated (Box 2)
  - 50. John McLoughlin, 38 Ways to Succeed with Your Client, 1977 (Box 2)
  - 51. Ten Ways to Restore Vitality to Old, Worn-out Products--Wall Street Journal, 1982 Feb. 18 (Box 2)
  - 52. Calculating Commercial Exposure for Pool Policy, undated (Box 2)
  - 53. Judy Bernstein, 10 Ways to Plan a Successful Press Party (Box 2)
  - 54. Benton Bowles, Notes on the Application of New Technology to Media (Box 2)
  - 55. Richard Scheidker, What Every Account Representative Should Know about the Law and Advertising, 1982 (Box 2)
  - 56. Food Guidelines Case History, undated (Box 2)
  - 57. Saatchi Saatchi, Principles, undated (Box 2)
  - 58. David Ogilvy and Joel Raphaelson, Research on Advertising Techniques that Don't Work, 1982 (Box 2)
  - 59. Herbert Stein, Knowing the Unknowable, 1982 (Box 2)
  - 60. Advertising Research Classics (9 articles)--Journal of Advertising Research, 1982 Sept. (Box 2)
  - 61. Young Rubicam, Acquisition Venture Criteria, undated (Box 2)
  - 62. Ogilvy Mather, How To's of Corporate Advertising, 1982 (Box 2)
  - 63. ACLI (American Council of Life Insurance) Annual Meeting, 1982 (Box 2)
  - 64. David Ogilvy, Choose Advertising--You'll Never Be Bored, undated (Box 2)
  - 65. Dorothy Sarnoff, Make the Most of Your Best (excerpt), undated (Box 2)
  - 66. Coopers Lybrand, Checking into an Acquisition Candidate, 1982 (Box 2)
  - 67. Allan Stewart, How to Tell a Market-Oriented Company When You See One, 1983 (Box 2)
  - 68. [empty folder] (Box 2)
  - 69. BBDO, The Use and Abuse of Qualitative Research, 1983 (Box 2)
  - 70. Allan Stewart, Marketing and GTE, 1983 (Box 2)
  - 71. Cable TV, 1983 (Box 2)
  - 72. Barbara Feigin, Responsible Advertising: Talking To and With Consumers, 1983 (Box 2)
  - 73. Steven Felsher, notes from Ogilvy Mather annual meeting, 1983 (Box 2)
  - 74. Training at Ogilvy Mather, 1982 (Box 2)
  - 75. Edward Meyer, Saatchi Saatchi Compton annual report, 1983 (Box 2)
  - 76. Dick Karp, No Guts No Glory, undated (Box 2)
  - 77. The Professions, from Career Insights, undated (Box 2)
  - 78. Alvin Achenbaum, How to Choose an Advertising Agency, 1983 (Box 2)
  - 79. Barbara Lippert, Where We've Been and Where We're Going, 1983 (Box 2)
  - 80. Edward Meyer, Guaranteeing Your Corporate Advertising Investment, 1983 (Box 2)
  - 81. How Avertising Works (Journal of Advertising Research), 1983 Sept. (Box 2)
  - 82. George Weidemann, Direct Marketing Megatrends, 1983 (Box 2)
  - 83. The Function of Advertising, 1983 (Box 2)
  - 84. Carolyn Carter, The Future of Advertising--Advertising Megatrends, 1983 (Box 2)
  - 85. Norman Berry, How to Win by Nurturing, Loving and Supporting Ideas, 1983 (Box 3)
  - 86. Paul Shay, Six Mental Maps for Planning the Future, undated (Box 3)
  - 87. Stephen Oresman, Management and Technology Change, 1982 (Box 3)
  - 88. International Paper, Executive Survival Kit, undated (Box 3)
  - 89. Booz-Allen Hamilton, New Products Management for the 1980s, 1982 (Box 3)
  - 90. Malcolm McDougall, Just Deserts: Why Clients Get the Advertising They Deserve, 1984 (Box 3)
  - 91. John Naisbitt, The Year Ahead, 1984 (Box 3)
  - 92. McKinsey, Channel Strategies: Maintaining Brand Strategies, 1984 (Box 3)
  - 93. James MacLachlan, Making a Message Memorable and Persuasive, 1983 (Box 3)
  - 94. [empty folder] (Box 3)
  - 95. [empty folder] (Box 3)
  - 96. Robert Chestnut, Human Problems in Coping with Technology, 1984 (Box 3)
  - 97. Futures Group Reports, 1984 (Box 3)
  - 98. Jan van Aal, Corporate Culture, 1984 (Box 3)
  - 99. Creating and Maintaining a Superior, Loyal Staff, undated (Box 3)
  - 100. Notes on the Application of New Technology to Media, undated (Box 3)
  - 101. Research in Service of Brand Character Building Advertising, 1984 (Box 3)
  - 102. Carol Herman speech to Harvard Business School, 1984 (Box 3)
  - 103. Network 30-second price list (Box 3)
  - 104. Jayne Zenaty, New Communications Technology in the year 2000, 1984 (Box 3)
  - 105. AAAA speeches on advertising in the year 2000, 1984 (Box 3)
  - 106. Speech on global marketing given at Florida Atlantic (Box 3)
  - 107. Leo Shapiro and Dwight Bohmbach, Heavy Gazers Pace Consumers, 1984 (Box 3)
  - 108. Fifteen-second commercials, 1984 (Box 3)
  - 109. Bill Giles, Renault case history, undated (Box 3)
  - 110. Barbara Feigin, Perceptions of Grey in the International Arena, 1984 (Box 3)
  - 111. Communications industry report, undated (Box 3)
  - 112. Salomon Brothers, Advertising and the Economy, 1985 (Box 3)
  - 113. Mike Isaacson, The Why and the How of Making the Whole of Your Agency More Creative, 1985 (Box 3)
  - 114. Barry Day, The Seven DeADly Sins, undated (Box 3)
  - 115. Paul Harper, Quality People Hold Key to Success, 1985 (Box 3)
  - 116. George Weidemann, 1984 and Direct Marketing, 1985 (Box 3)
  - 117. Barbara Feigin, Market Target Selection, 1985 (Box 3)
  - 118. Alvin Achenbaum, Ten Impediments to Marketing Productivity, 1985 (Box 3)
  - 119. InterPublic, New Recommendation, 1985 (Box 3)
  - 120. Peter Warren, Taking the Conflict out of Conflicts, 1984 (Box 3)
  - 121. Edward Meyer, Power Retailing: What Can It Teach Us?, 1985 (Box 3)
  - 122. Tom Peters and Nancy Austin, A Passion for Excellence, 1985 (Box 3)
  - 123. Ogilvy Mather Listening Post, 1985 April (Box 3)
  - 124. Robert Strozier, Attack at Dawn, 1985 (Box 3)
  - 125. The Economy: What Makes It Tick, undated (Box 4)
  - 126. The Experts Guide to the Baby Boomers, undated (Box 4)
  - 127. [empty folder] (Box 4)
  - 128. John Shannon, Re-Defining the Full Service Concept, 1985 (Box 4)
  - 129. New Developments in Test Marketing, 1985 (Box 4)
  - 130. John Marder, NK Seminar, 1985 (Box 4)
  - 131. Some facts about account management, 1985 (Box 4)
  - 132. VCRs Coming of Age: The Implications for Advertisers, 1985 (Box 4)
  - 133. Ed Buxton, Coke You Weren't First, 1985 (Box 4)
  - 134. American Affluence: Who's Really Behind the Move to High Ticket Purchases, undated (Box 4)
  - 135. Creativity in Business syllabus, 1984 (Box 4)
  - 136. Classy Client Comments to Those Classic Creations, 1985 (Box 4)
  - 137. Edward Meyer, Creativity in Business, undated (Box 4)
  - 138. Top Brands Don't Change, 1985 (Box 4)
  - 139. Robert Strozier, Attack at Dawn, 1985 (Box 4)
  - 140. The Function of the Agency Account Team to Champion the Business, 1986 (Box 4)
  - 141. Barbara Feigin, Beyond Positioning: What Role for Reasearch?, 1986 (Box 4)
  - 142. Interview with Ralph Salvino, undated (Box 4)
  - 143. The Male Food Shopper: How Men Are Changing Food Shopping in America, undated (Box 4)
  - 144. Carol Herman, speech to Harvard Business School, 1986 (Box 4)
  - 145. Yankelovich Monitor, 1985 (Box 4)
  - 146. AAAA, Longevity of Accounts in the Advertising Agency Business, 1985 (Box 4)
  - 147. B. McDonald, The Pacific '86, 1986 (Box 4)
  - 148. Decker, 7 Biggest Mistakes Business Presenters Make and How to Avoid Them, 1981 (Box 4)
  - 149. Shirley Young, Value Marketing, 1986 (Box 4)
  - 150. Norman Vale, International Marketing Conference speech, 1986 (Box 4)
  - 151. Trends in In-House Advertising, 1986 (Box 4)
  - 152. Advertising: How It Is Growing and Changing, undated (Box 4)
  - 153. Richard Stevenson, Ad Agency Mergers Changing the Business, 1986 (Box 4)
  - 154. Robert Burnett and Barbara Feigin, Global Communication: A Real Life Odyssey, 1986 (Box 4)
  - 155. Graham Phillips, Marketing in the New World of Scanners, 1986 (Box 4)
  - 156. Joseph Smith, The Leading Edge, 1984 (Box 4)
  - 157. Michael Wallbridge, New Uses for Databased Communications, 1986 (Box 4)
  - 158. Nancy Salz, 1986 Salz Survey of Advertiser Agency Relations (Box 4)
  - 159. Edward Meyer, Trends in Agency Business, 1986 (Box 5)
  - 160. R.V. Goldstein, Outlook of Procter Gamble ad chief, 1986 (Box 5)
  - 161. Richard Stevenson, Marketing Shifts to Promotion, 1986 (Box 5)
  - 162. John Quelch, Marketing the Premium Product, undated (Box 5)
  - 163. Nancy Yoshihara, As Companies Get Tight with Ad Budgets, Agencies and Media Firms Feel Squeezed, 1986 (Box 5)
  - 164. Joanne Lipman, As Network TV Fades, Many Advertisers Try Age-Old Promotions, 1986 (Box 5)
  - 165. Yoram Wind, The Myth of Globalization, 1986 (Box 5)
  - 166. Michael Porter, The Strategic Role of International Marketing, 1986 (Box 5)
  - 167. Philip Kotler, Global Standardization: Courting Danger, 1986 (Box 5)
  - 168. Jagcish Seth, Global Markets or Global Competition?, undated (Box 5)
  - 169. Francoise Simon-Miller, World Marketing: Going Global or Acting Local? Five Expert Viewpoints, 1986 (Box 5)
  - 170. Christine Dugas, How Advertising is Reshaping Madison Avenue, 1986 (Box 5)
  - 171. Greg Ostroff, Advertising Industry Overview, 1986 (Box 5)
  - 172. Nancy Youman, Liquor Biz Eyes Direct Mail, 1986 (Box 5)
  - 173. Edward Meyer, The Art of Excellence in the New Age of Advertising, 1986 (Box 5)
  - 174. Dick Karp, What Makes Advertising Great?, 1986 (Box 5)
  - 175. The American Dream: 1980s Style, 1986 (Box 5)
  - 176. The Boomer Generation as Consumer$, 1986 (Box 5)
  - 177. Graham Phillips, The Role of Advertising or the Importance of a Strong Brand Franchise, 1986 (Box 5)
  - 178. David McCall, Getting Your Money's Worth, 1986 (Box 5)
  - 179. Alvin Achenbaum, The Perils of Niche Marketing, 1986 (Box 5)
  - 180. William E. Phillips, Why Your Advertising Agency Needs a Better Product, 1986 (Box 5)
  - 181. Personal Marketing, undated (Box 5)
  - 182. CBS Strategic Review: U.S. National Advertising Market, undated (Box 5)
  - 183. Ruth Ziff, Consumer Markets, 1986 (Box 5)
  - 184. Au Clair de la Pub (English translation), undated (Box 5)
  - 185. Charles Channon, The Role of the Account Planner, 1986 (Box 5)
  - 186. OJC Shannon, Planning for Quality, Profit and Growth, 1986 (Box 5)
  - 187. William E. Phillips, Can Commodity Thinking Kill Established Brands?, 1986 (Box 5)
  - 188. Wall Street Transcript, 1987 Feb.2 (Box 5)
  - 189. Creating a Sustainable Competitive Edge, undated (Box 5)
  - 190. James Jordan, ANA annual meeting speech, 1987 (Box 5)
  - 191. Royal Bank of Canada Monthly Letter, 1950-1964 (Box 5)
  - 192. Mary Connors, Catching TV Viewers in the Act of Being Themselves, 1987 (Box 5)
  - 193. Public Pulse, 31 Major Trends Shaping the Future of American Business, 1987 (Box 5)
  - 194. Changing Goals/Lifestyles/Attitudes Among American Women in the late 1980s and 1990s, 1987 (Box 5)
  - 195. Observations on a New Job, undated (Box 5)
  - 196. Reuben Mark, Colgate's 10 Commandments, undated (Box 5)
  - 197. Peter Barnet, First Class: How to Market Premium Products, 1987 (Box 5)
  - 198. Phil Burton speech, undated (Box 5)
  - 199. J. Brendon Ryan, How to Build and Develop a Terrific Staff, undated (Box 5)
  - 200. Edward Meyer, Advertising: A Shot in the Arm or a Shot in the Dark?, 1987 (Box 5)
  - 201. What Makes a Likeable Commercial?, undated (Box 5)
  - 202. Barbara Feigin, The Ultraconsumers: Massive and Here to Stay, 1987 (Box 5)
  - 203. John Quelch, Marketing the Premium Product, 1987 (Box 5)
  - 204. Intergold, Our Resons for Conducting an Agency Search, 1987 (Box 5)
  - 205. Agency selection criteria, 1987 (Box 5)
  - 206. Myron Magnet, The Money Society, 1987 (Box 5)
  - 207. Ken Roman and Joel Raphaelson, How to Write Better, undated (Box 5)
  - 208. Andrew Kershaw, How to Make Agency Presentations, undated (Box 5)
  - 209. Public Pulse, 31 Major Trends Shaping the Future of American Business, 1987 (Box 6)
  - 210. Norman Berry, Revitilizing Brands, undated (Box 6)
  - 211. Tony DeGregorio, Finding a Good Idea is Knowing Where to Look, undated (Box 6)
  - 212. Alvin Achenbaum, Feeling the Squeeze, 1987 (Box 6)
  - 213. Career in agency account management (Box 6)
  - 214. John Merwin, We Don't Learn from Clients, We Learn from Each Other, 1987 (Box 6)
  - 215. Yankelovich Monitor Overview of Food Trends (Box 6)
  - 216. Goldman Sachs, Overview and Database Adevtising Industry, 1987 (Box 6)
  - 217. David Leddick, The Europeanization of America, undated (Box 6)
  - 218. Xu Bai-Yi, A Brief History of Advertising in China, undated (Box 6)
  - 219. Achenbaum at Large, 1987 (Box 6)
  - 220. The Shift of Marketing Dollars from Advertising to Promotion, 1987 (Box 6)
  - 221. Phillip Smith, The Seven Principles of Disciplined Creativity, 1987 (Box 6)
  - 222. Laurie Peterson, Harvard's Quelch on the Future of Promotion, 1987 (Box 6)
  - 223. The Media Consumer (Box 6)
  - 224. The Shift of Marketing Dollars from Advertising to Promotion, 1987 (Box 6)
  - 225. George Weidemann, Personal Marketing When the Consumer Talks Back, 1987 (Box 6)
  - 226. Walter Wriston, A New Kind of Free Speech, 1987 (Box 6)
  - 227. What is Planning?, undated (Box 6)
  - 228. The Food World of Teenagers, 1988 (Box 6)
  - 229. Manfred F.R. Kets de Vries, The Dark Side of CEO Succession, 1988 (Box 6)
  - 230. Kenneth Roman, How to Manage Ideas, undated (Box 6)
  - 231. Reuben Mark, Colgate's 10 Commandments, undated (Box 6)
  - 232. James Heekin, How I Would Get More Creativity from My Agency, 1968 (Box 6)
  - 233. Douglas Haley, Industry Promotion and Advertising Trends: Why Are They Important?, 1987 (Box 6)
  - 234. Marie Greener, Insights Gained from Group Sessions among Creatives: The Role of Research, 1987 (Box 6)
  - 235. Barbara Feigin, The Role of Agency Research Departments: A Perspective for the 90s, 1988 (Box 6)
  - 236. Marie Greener and Joseph Gearing, A Study on the Creative's Perspective on Copy Development Research, 1985 (Box 6)
  - 237. Curvin O'Reilly, Why Some People Have More Ideas, 1988 (Box 6)
  - 238. What Makes Advertising Great, 1986 (Box 6)
  - 239. Carolyn Carter, New Aspirations for Advertising: What the Death of the Yuppie Means to Madison Avenue, 1988 (Box 6)
  - 240. Barbara Feigin, The Ultraconsumers: Massive and Here to Stay, 1988 (Box 6)
  - 241. Edward Meyer, Creative Catalysts: Forces that Will Shape Advertising in the 1990s, 1988 (Box 6)
  - 242. Edward Meyer, 1988 A Watershed Year for Creativity (Box 6)
  - 243. Saatchi Saatchi Business Services Network, 1988 (Box 6)
  - 244. Weighing the Balance: Advantages of Agency Media Service vs. In-House Media Operation, 1987 (Box 6)
  - 245. Advertising as a Productivity Force, 1988 (Box 6)
  - 246. Corporate Survival: Teamwork is the Key, undated (Box 6)
  - 247. New York Times Poll Nutrition Survey, 1987 (Box 6)
  - 248. Zapping of TV Ads Appears Pervasive, 1988 (Box 6)
  - 249. Old Standbys Hold Their Own, 1988 (Box 6)
  - 250. A World Without Advertising, 1988 (Box 6)
  - 251. Household and Lifestyle Trends, 1988 (Box 6)
  - 252. Marisa Manley, Before You Sign That Lease..., 1988 (Box 6)
  - 253. General Foods compensation policy, 1988 (Box 6)
  - 254. Lee Orkin negotiation seminar, 1988 (Box 6)
  - 255. J.E. Pepper, Passion in Advertising, 1988 (Box 6)
  - 256. Research Today: Where the Action Is (ARF conference transcripts), 1988 (Box 6)
  - 257. Laurie Petersen, Global Promotion, 1988 (Box 6)
  - 258. Lee Orkin compensation/negotiation seminar, 1988 (Box 7)
  - 259. Gene Bylinsky, Technology in the Year 2000, 1988 (Box 7)
  - 260. Movies on Our Minds: A Few Creative Thoughts on How to Build Box Office for Warner Brothers, 1988 (Box 7)
  - 261. IBM Total Quality, 1988 (Box 7)
  - 262. George Will, Bulwer-Lytton Fiction Contest, 1987 (Box 7)
  - 263. Sports Illustrated (U.S. Hockey Team Olympic win), 1988 (Box 7)
  - 264. Ogilvy Orchestration, We Sell or Else, undated (Box 7)
  - 265. Acquisition and Diversification, undated (Box 7)
  - 266. Ultress Success, Connecting with the Nineties, 1988 (Box 7)
  - 267. Bob Schoenfein, Love Lessons: The Wooing, the Romancing, the Winning of New Business, 1988 (Box 7)
  - 268. Graham Phillips, Agency Compensation: Which End of the Telescope?, 1988 (Box 7)
  - 269. Alec Gerster, Demanding Media Consumer, 1988 (Box 7)
  - 270. Mystique Marketing, 1988 (Box 7)
  - 271. Robert Bloom, The Agency of the Future, 1988 (Box 7)
  - 272. Advertising Age, The Power of Advertising: A Unifying Force for the 21st Century, 1988 Nov. 9 (Box 7)
  - 273. Thomas Keiser, Negotiating with a Customer You Can't Afford to Lose, 1988 (Box 7)
  - 274. Negotiating Compensation with Clients, 1988 (Box 7)
  - 275. Jeffrey Trachtenberg, Viewer Fatigue?, 1988 (Box 7)
  - 276. George Will, Impact of Technological Change on the World, 1989 (Box 7)
  - 277. Advertising vs. Promotion, undated (Box 7)
  - 278. Merrill Lynch, Advertising Agencies Industry Review, 1988 (Box 7)
  - 279. AAAA, The Advertising Agency of the Future, 1989 (Box 7)
  - 280. The Impact of Advertising Expenditures on Profits for Consumer Businesses, 1987 (Box 7)
  - 281. Advertising's Big Bang, 1989 (Box 7)
  - 282. Phillip Rawstorne, The Secrets of Market Domination, 1989 (Box 7)
  - 283. James Capel, The Global Advertising Marketplace, 1988 (Box 7)
  - 284. Media Advertising TWST roundtable, 1989 (Box 8)
  - 285. Brand character project, 1981 (Box 8)
  - 286. How Advertising Works, 1989 (Box 8)
  - 287. AAAA, The Value Side of Productivity, 1989 (Box 8)
  - 288. Magid Abraham and Leonard Lodish, Advertising Works, 1989 (Box 8)
  - 289. Hal Riney, How to Not Fire Your Ad Agency, 1989 (Box 8)
  - 290. Michael Turner, What Makes a Good AE, 1980 (Box 8)
  - 291. Effective Account Management, undated (Box 8)
  - 292. William Weed, How to Create a Creative Climate, undated (Box 8)
  - 293. William Phillips, Principles of Account Management, 1975 (Box 8)
  - 294. Jerry Zaret, Creativity or A Marshmallow a Day Keeps Your Freckles on Straight, undated (Box 8)
  - 295. Alex Biel, The Accountability of Advertising, 1989 (Box 8)
  - 296. Bob Schoenfein, Seven Deadly Sins of Credentials Presentations, 1989 (Box 8)
  - 297. Gary Hamel and C.K. Prahalad, Strategic Intent, 1989 (Box 8)
  - 298. Kevin McCormack, Client compensation, 1989 (Box 8)
  - 299. Implementing Total Quality, undated (Box 8)
  - 300. Ken Dychtwald, The Shifting American Marketplace, undated (Box 8)
  - 301. Why People Don't Read Long-Copy Ads, undated (Box 8)